Listen up, everybody!
If I die in this fight,
this guy is your new chief!
And I won't accept any objections,
protests, or other noise!
Come at me like you're gonna kill me!
Out of everyone I've ever fought before,
you're in the top grade.
Indeed. Very well. And if I die...
Yeah. I'll let your female go unharmed.
She's not "mine" yet.
Hmph, you're really
making a bid for her, aren't you?
Is that plant monster
really that fine a female?
Extremely so.
I'd like to see for myself.
If I win, I think I'll undress her
before returning her.
Then it seems I now have
an especially powerful reason not to lose.
You're really head-over-heels
for her, aren't you?
Yeah, I'm head-over-heels.
Ha! Then beat me, and prove it!
That's what I intend to do.
Ha-ha, you survived that, huh?
You're a monk?
What's the matter? Aren't you going
to use that ability Frost Pain has?
Long ago, I was beaten
by the one who wielded it.
These are the wounds I received at the time.
If you activate it,
you might be able to beat me.
Sorry, but I don't plan to use it.
Hmm, what are you, too stingy?
After you've exchanged blows with me,
do you still think I'm that way?
No, you're not. Sorry,
you didn't deserve that.
But if you aren't going to use it,
then here I come!
Iron Skin!
Damn it!
I've lost!
Are you okay?
I'll cast some healing
magic on you, right now.
Middle Cure Wounds.
Hey, now, you're making me jealous.
Would you mind healing me, too, white stuff?
Okay, okay.
It hurts quite a bit.
Feels like I got frozen to the bone.
Frost Pain carries a chill in its blade,
and it delivers a little bit of
cold damage to those struck by it.
That's why you just
kept taking his attacks, right?
I thought that if you
didn't use that ability it has,
it would be just another cold sword.
Now that both of our wounds have been healed,
would it be okay if we got down to business?
Yeah! Or it would be, but first, drinks!
We can ease these annoying talks
with alcohol! You get me, right?
No, I don't!
Hey, plant monster.
Have you finished talking?
Broadly speaking, yes.
So what are you going to do?
Huh?
We're gonna fight, of course!
You really are a fiend for fighting.
Don't flatter me; you'll make me blush.
So, can we win?
I don't know.
Do you remember the words
of that monster that came as a herald?
Sorry, I was asleep.
It said to us, "Offer a
desperate resistance."
That's galling. They're looking down
on us right from the start.
That's right, our foe holds us
in complete contempt.
That's an indication of
how much force they must possess.
Which is why we're going to
obliterate their hubris.
Ha! Nice!
But even if we give
their pride a good thrashing,
I don't think it gains us anything.
I think I would prefer
holding on to life, even if it's in chains.
I want you to listen to all this carefully.
If we're under their rule,
we may not even be able to do this.
But maybe we can. Isn't that right?
I'm not so sure.
I doubt that any being who would
watch on in enjoyment as we die
would have any mercy.
True enough. What I'm trying to say, though,
is don't get killed.
I won't. Not until I hear your answer.
Ho, it's coming into sight.
Yeah, that's the Razor Tail village,
who they said would be first.
Those from the other villages
are probably already there.
This is all more than I can resist.
Welcome back, my little brother.
Yeah. I've returned with good news, Brother.
Hmm...
What's the deal with the plant monster?
This is the female I love.
With a mind toward marriage--
I see. So much for "I can't get married."
You just didn't have anyone
you were in love with, right?
Now then, I am the chief of
the Green Claw tribe, Shasuryu Shasha.
Those we sent out as scouts
have just returned.
Why don't we go listen
to their detailed report?
The enemy's main stronghold is in the forest.
They number just under around 5,000.
"Small Fang Tribe"
"Chief Sukyu Juju"
Their main force consist of
zombies and skeletons.
We did not locate the one
who appears to be the army's leader.
Hmm, our forces number roughly 1,300.
They outnumber us by over three to one.
So we just have to take on
three or four of them each, right?
That's a cinch.
First, we have to establish
a chain of command.
Should we form brigades
centered around the chiefs?
No, we should have a separate unit
consisting of only chiefs.
Hmm...?
Plan is to make... elite unit?
"Razor Tail Tribe"
"Chief Kyuku Zuzu"
That's right. The enemy's numbers are great.
It may be necessary to go after their leader.
And if there are any stronger foes,
we'll need to strike them
with smaller, elite forces.
But that will leave our side
without commanders, too, won't it?
All right, what if we have the separate unit
issue orders from the
rear to the head hunters,
coordinating things as the situation demands?
Four days until the enemy strikes.
We don't have a moment to waste.
Message.
Attention all forces. Advance!
Ah, so Cocytus has started
advancing the army.
Yes. According to Entoma's message,
everything is not exceeding our expectations.
As you ordered, Lord Ains,
Cocytus himself is not heading out,
and they are attacking with
only the forces they have been given.
I see. It's not exactly the outcome I wanted,
but the question is, what
will we get out of it?
There they are.
Listen up, all of you Lizard Men!
We recognize that the enemy is great!
However, there is nothing to be afraid of!
For the first time in history,
our five tribes have formed an alliance!
It is through this alliance
that we have become one tribe,
and the ancestor spirits
of the five tribes will protect us all!
Let us defeat the enemy,
and offer victory to the ancestor spirits!
To war!
They're using the cavalry to get behind them,
surround them, and wipe them out, is that it?
I think it's time for us
to make our first play, as well.
Shoot them!
Are they thumbing their noses at us?
I can't seem to make sense of them.
Is it possible that they don't
have any commanders?
So does that mean they think
they just needed greater numbers?
They're mocking us!
Still, we should reduce the enemy's numbers
as much as possible, while we can.
Tch, I wanna get out there, too!
Patience, Zenberu.
Just be patient
until the enemy's leader appears.
We can't afford to reveal the elite unit yet.
I can't believe they can summon
Swamp Elementals in such a short time.
Working together really is an amazing thing.
Indeed. After that last war,
we did exchange small bits of information.
After this incident is over,
there are more things I'd like to try.
Right, Zaryusu.
I underestimated the Lizard Men's morale.
Message.
Demiurge...
Yes, my friend. What in the world
has caused you to Message me?
As it happens...
I see. So what would you like me to do?
I need some advice. If this defeat
is mine alone, I can accept it.
However, I can't do anything
to disgrace the Supreme One.
Does Lord Ains really want you to win?
What? What do you mean by that?
I mean, why did Lord Ains
raise an army of such low-level servants?
Perhaps...
Lord Ains wished for you
to think for yourself,
and gather some intelligence
to help you pursue victory?
It could be part of a plan
to promote your awareness.
Additionally, the name of Nazarick
was never put forth.
And you were forbidden to move on them,
as well. Which would mean...
Hmm? Demiurge?
Cocytus, I apologize,
but something has just come up.
I wish you victory.
It's too late to do anything now, isn't it?
Then there's no choice
but to send in the reserves.
I'm giving you an order,
Elder Lich in command.
Advance! Show the Lizard Men your power!
Okay, carry the seriously
wounded to the village.
The rest of you, follow us--
Run! That one isn't like
the other enemies up to now!
You all head back and tell the chiefs
and Zaryusu about this!
We'll buy you some time!
I, Iguva, will secure His victory.
It looks like we're up this time,
that's for sure.
Yeah, that's a powerful one.
Is that the army's commander?
Even if it isn't, there's no doubt
he's their ace in reserve.
Right. But how are we going to get near him?
It looks like he has a magic range
of about 100 meters.
You're right. That's what we can do.
Zaryusu...?
Fools. You think that slow-moving beast
can traverse this distance?!
Insufferable brute! Die!
Why won't it stop?!
Why does it keep coming?!
Icy Burst!
Wha--?
Thanks, Rororo.
Impossible!
Icy Burst!
Shoot as many as you like!
I'll dispel them all!
In that case, take my
thunderbolts! Lightning!
Let me handle this.
Resistance... Massive!
You saved us!
Ha-ha, no sweat.
Summon Undead 4th!
I am Iguva, an Elder Lich
in the service of the Great One.
If you bow your heads,
I will make your deaths painless.
In that case, here is your answer:
Hell no!
Then realize that you have
rejected my final offer of mercy
as you suffer a death racked with anguish!
No, you go back to
the world of the dead, Iguva!
Forward, Zaryusu!
Know terror! Scare!
Lion's Heart!
Zaryusu!
Pestiferous fool! Lightning!
Crusch!
--Light--
--Too slow!
Magic won't help you at this range!
Don't underestimate me, Lizard Man!
Zaryusu, I'm finished here!
You take it... from... here...
Middle Cure Wounds!
You won't best me!
I won't have you looking down on me!
Area-of-effect magic, at this range?
No!
Icy Burst!
Hmph, you only hurt yourself,
not knowing that cold doesn't work on me.
Now, where is he...?
I-I am a servant created by the One!
I will not be brought down...
...by something like this!
Die, Lizard Man!
Rororo...
Zenberu...
Crusch...
Impossible! How can you move?!
You monster!
You're... finished!
Lord... Ains...
...forgive... me...
Our gratitude to you!
Lord Cocytus,
Lord Ains is calling for you.
Understood.
Nicely done.
But it truly was a close one.